<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-24T09:15:49+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LightCity Teaching Fellowship Bible Study Resources</title><subtitle>This site is for the study of the Bible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Psalm 149</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Psalm%20149/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Psalm 149" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Psalms-149</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Psalm%20149/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Psalm 149</h1></header>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>We will sing a new song at the resurrection.</li>
    <li>Playing the tambourine and harp in church is prophesying of the resurrection [Psa 149:3].</li><!--excerpt.end-->
    <li>Salvation is the garment of the priests. Our new bodies are called salvation/righteousness [Psa 149:3; 132:15,9].</li>
    <li>God is going to make the meek priests [Psa 149:3].</li>
    <li>The saints will carry out the judgment decreed against the princes (<em>spiritual and physical</em>) of this age [Psa 149:5-9].</li>
    <li>Though we will not have blood after the resurrection, we will have breath [Psa 150:6].</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Psalms" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Psalms" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Psalm 149 We will sing a new song at the resurrection. Playing the tambourine and harp in church is prophesying of the resurrection [Psa 149:3]. Salvation is the garment of the priests. Our new bodies are called salvation/righteousness [Psa 149:3; 132:15,9]. God is going to make the meek priests [Psa 149:3]. The saints will carry out the judgment decreed against the princes (spiritual and physical) of this age [Psa 149:5-9]. Though we will not have blood after the resurrection, we will have breath [Psa 150:6].]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Why%20Do%20Priests%20of%20the%20Law%20Wear%20Head%20Coverings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/why-do-Priests--wear-Head-Covering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Why%20Do%20Priests%20of%20the%20Law%20Wear%20Head%20Coverings/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings?</h1></header>
<h3>If The New Testament Forbids Head Coverings for Men in Prayer and Prophecy, Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings?</h3>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>Head covering is a part of the Priestley garment. It is required for the priesthood.
        <ol>
            <li>Turban/Mitre for the high priest [Exo 28:3-4, 36-38; Lev 8:9; 16:4; Zec 3:1,5; 6:9-11].</li>
            <li>Cap/Bonnet for the priests [Exo 28:40; 29:9; 39:28; Lev 8:13].</li>
        </ol>
    </li><!--excerpt.end-->
    <li>The priestly garment is for glory and beauty [Exo 28:2].</li>
    <li>The man is not to cover his head because he is the glory of God [1Co 11:7-9; Gen 1:26-28; 2:21-22].</li>
    <li>The woman is to cover hers because she's the glory of man [1Co 11:7-9; Gen 1:26-28; 2:21-22].</li>
    <li>Priests, not all men were commanded to cover their heads.</li>
    <li>Glory is a determiner of hierarchy.</li>
    <li>Therefore, in the hierarchy of the Law;
        <ol>
            <li>The priests are first, with the high priest being their head.</li>
            <li>Men are next in the hierarchy.</li>
            <li>Women come after men in the hierarchy.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>THE LAW OBSERVES THE SAME PRINCIPLE, BUT ONLY ADDS AN EXTRA LAYER ABOVE IT AS IT WILL BE AT THE FIRST RESURRECTION.</li>
    <li>The garments gave the priests greater glory in addition to the glory they had by creation.</li>
    <li>The garments elevated priests above men who were already elevated above women.</li>
    <li>What the Law does in shadows is what the first resurrection will do in reality. Saints will become priests, getting new bodies (<em>priestly garments</em>) at the first resurrection, and will be elevated above all other men [Mat 6:25,28,31-33; 2Cor 5:1-5].</li>
    <li>Though men are naturally elevated over women at creation, the saints (<em>men and women</em>) who partake of the first resurrection, get new bodies.</li>
    <li>The natural man covering is head is equivalent to the priests covering their turban, and this is contrary to God's will, as He does not want men to cover their glory.
        <ol>
            <li>The Priestly garment is for glory and for beauty [Exo 28:2]</li>
            <li>Therefore, the priests must not hide their glory and beauty.</li>
            <li>If the natural man &ndash; <em>being the glory of God</em>&ndash; covers his head, then he is covering his glory and beauty.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Women are to cover their heads.
        <ol>
            <li>Woman is man&rsquo;s image, while man is God&rsquo;s image.</li>
            <li>This means woman is also God&rsquo;s image (<em>although with slightly different characteristics</em>)</li>
            <li>Women are to cover their heads (<em>glory</em>) as a way to show that although they are also God&rsquo;s glory, they are only so through [because of] man.</li>
            <li>They are to cover their head to show that though they are also in God&rsquo;s image, they are under man.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Until the time of the new order, natural man represents Christ and God on earth and is not to cover his head in the presence of God [Heb 9:10; Rev 21:5].</li>
    <li>Those who ask contentious questions on this matter are as the Sadducees who wanted to mock the doctrine of the resurrection by giving the example of a hypothetical woman who was married to multiple men who died. They did not believe in the resurrection,
        but were looking for a reason to rebel against the doctrine. If they could show that the doctrine promoted adultery/polyandry in the kingdom, then they could dismiss it as obviously illogical.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Exodus" /><category term="1-Corinthians" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Exodus" /><category term="1-Corinthians" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings? If The New Testament Forbids Head Coverings for Men in Prayer and Prophecy, Why Do Priests of the Law Wear Head Coverings? Head covering is a part of the Priestley garment. It is required for the priesthood. Turban/Mitre for the high priest [Exo 28:3-4, 36-38; Lev 8:9; 16:4; Zec 3:1,5; 6:9-11]. Cap/Bonnet for the priests [Exo 28:40; 29:9; 39:28; Lev 8:13]. The priestly garment is for glory and beauty [Exo 28:2]. The man is not to cover his head because he is the glory of God [1Co 11:7-9; Gen 1:26-28; 2:21-22]. The woman is to cover hers because she's the glory of man [1Co 11:7-9; Gen 1:26-28; 2:21-22]. Priests, not all men were commanded to cover their heads. Glory is a determiner of hierarchy. Therefore, in the hierarchy of the Law; The priests are first, with the high priest being their head. Men are next in the hierarchy. Women come after men in the hierarchy. THE LAW OBSERVES THE SAME PRINCIPLE, BUT ONLY ADDS AN EXTRA LAYER ABOVE IT AS IT WILL BE AT THE FIRST RESURRECTION. The garments gave the priests greater glory in addition to the glory they had by creation. The garments elevated priests above men who were already elevated above women. What the Law does in shadows is what the first resurrection will do in reality. Saints will become priests, getting new bodies (priestly garments) at the first resurrection, and will be elevated above all other men [Mat 6:25,28,31-33; 2Cor 5:1-5]. Though men are naturally elevated over women at creation, the saints (men and women) who partake of the first resurrection, get new bodies. The natural man covering is head is equivalent to the priests covering their turban, and this is contrary to God's will, as He does not want men to cover their glory. The Priestly garment is for glory and for beauty [Exo 28:2] Therefore, the priests must not hide their glory and beauty. If the natural man &ndash; being the glory of God&ndash; covers his head, then he is covering his glory and beauty. Women are to cover their heads. Woman is man&rsquo;s image, while man is God&rsquo;s image. This means woman is also God&rsquo;s image (although with slightly different characteristics) Women are to cover their heads (glory) as a way to show that although they are also God&rsquo;s glory, they are only so through [because of] man. They are to cover their head to show that though they are also in God&rsquo;s image, they are under man. Until the time of the new order, natural man represents Christ and God on earth and is not to cover his head in the presence of God [Heb 9:10; Rev 21:5]. Those who ask contentious questions on this matter are as the Sadducees who wanted to mock the doctrine of the resurrection by giving the example of a hypothetical woman who was married to multiple men who died. They did not believe in the resurrection, but were looking for a reason to rebel against the doctrine. If they could show that the doctrine promoted adultery/polyandry in the kingdom, then they could dismiss it as obviously illogical.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exhortation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Exhortation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exhortation" /><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Exhortation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Exhortation/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Exhortation</h1></header>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>The blind and the lame are enemies of the King and will not enter His palace [2Sam 5:8].</li>
    <li>Joseph was as diligent as the angel who was sent to deliver the message to Daniel. The angel, despite being resisted by the prince of Persia, did not return to God but waited 21 days till reinforcement came [Dan 10:12-14]. Joseph too when
        he was sent by his father to locate his brothers persisted in his search for them until he found them, even though he did not find them where they were meant to be [Gen 37:12-17].<!--excerpt.end-->
        <ol>
            <li>The same Joseph did not ignore the sad countenance of the butler and the baker in prison &ndash; though it did not concern him &ndash; and went ahead to help them [Gen 40].</li>
            <li>Joseph also did not stop at interpreting Pharoah&rsquo;s dreams, but proceeded to give him counsel &ndash; though hid counsel was not solicited by Pharoah [Gen 41:25-37].</li>
            <li>People today would frown at this kind of behaviour; they mock people who offer unsolicited help, and those who go the extra mile to help others, and do the work they are given.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Women were made to help man. Marriage is an office for them, and God is the job creator. Marriage is work.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Year-2023" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exhortation The blind and the lame are enemies of the King and will not enter His palace [2Sam 5:8]. Joseph was as diligent as the angel who was sent to deliver the message to Daniel. The angel, despite being resisted by the prince of Persia, did not return to God but waited 21 days till reinforcement came [Dan 10:12-14]. Joseph too when he was sent by his father to locate his brothers persisted in his search for them until he found them, even though he did not find them where they were meant to be [Gen 37:12-17]. The same Joseph did not ignore the sad countenance of the butler and the baker in prison &ndash; though it did not concern him &ndash; and went ahead to help them [Gen 40]. Joseph also did not stop at interpreting Pharoah&rsquo;s dreams, but proceeded to give him counsel &ndash; though hid counsel was not solicited by Pharoah [Gen 41:25-37]. People today would frown at this kind of behaviour; they mock people who offer unsolicited help, and those who go the extra mile to help others, and do the work they are given. Women were made to help man. Marriage is an office for them, and God is the job creator. Marriage is work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Value of a Soul</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/The%20Value%20of%20a%20Soul/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Value of a Soul" /><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Value-of-a-Soul</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/The%20Value%20of%20a%20Soul/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>The Value of a Soul</h1></header>
<ol>
    <li>The resurrection is extremely valuable
        <ol>
            <!--excerpt.start--><li>The value of <strong>a</strong> soul is too costly, and no payment is ever enough [Psa 49:8].</li>
            <li>Jesus says <strong>a</strong> soul is more costly than the entire world [Mat 16:26].</li><!--excerpt.end-->
            <li>This means the resurrection for <strong>each</strong> soul is more valuable than the entire earth.</li>
            <li>Each resurrected saint is worth more than the entire earth.</li>
            <li>The redemption is giving new glorious bodies.</li>
            <li>Power-wise, the resurrected body of each saint is more powerful than this entire world [Eph 1:17-20].</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Since God gives each saint power greater than the earth at the resurrection, then:
        <ol>
            <li>The least among us has power over the earth</li>
            <li>Why would one have the power to create things if he is not to create?</li>
            <li>Is the power to create just for bringing us back to life? Is there not more?</li>
            <li>God did not just make Esther queen because He wanted the king to have a new wife, but because He wanted to save Israel. In the same way, God gives us the resurrection &ndash; with the power that accompanies it, the power greater than the world
                &ndash; for a purpose beyond the resurrection; a purpose beyond this world.</li>
            <li>God gives us creation power (<em>seeing as our bodies are more powerful than the earth</em>), perhaps because He needs us to use creation power.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>God said Abraham&rsquo;s seed would be as countable as the stars of heaven. Meaning, not just that they would be innumerable, but also that they will shine like the stars &ndash; as Daniel&rsquo;s prophecy confirms [Gen 15:5; Dan 12:2-3].</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Year-2023" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Value of a Soul The resurrection is extremely valuable The value of a soul is too costly, and no payment is ever enough [Psa 49:8]. Jesus says a soul is more costly than the entire world [Mat 16:26]. This means the resurrection for each soul is more valuable than the entire earth. Each resurrected saint is worth more than the entire earth. The redemption is giving new glorious bodies. Power-wise, the resurrected body of each saint is more powerful than this entire world [Eph 1:17-20]. Since God gives each saint power greater than the earth at the resurrection, then: The least among us has power over the earth Why would one have the power to create things if he is not to create? Is the power to create just for bringing us back to life? Is there not more? God did not just make Esther queen because He wanted the king to have a new wife, but because He wanted to save Israel. In the same way, God gives us the resurrection &ndash; with the power that accompanies it, the power greater than the world &ndash; for a purpose beyond the resurrection; a purpose beyond this world. God gives us creation power (seeing as our bodies are more powerful than the earth), perhaps because He needs us to use creation power. God said Abraham&rsquo;s seed would be as countable as the stars of heaven. Meaning, not just that they would be innumerable, but also that they will shine like the stars &ndash; as Daniel&rsquo;s prophecy confirms [Gen 15:5; Dan 12:2-3].]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Proverbs 31</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Proverbs%2031/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proverbs 31" /><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Proverbs-31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Proverbs%2031/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Proverbs 31</h1></header>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>King Lemuel received counsel from his mother, and his mother will share in the glory attributed to him, for she was a part of his upbringing.
        <ol>
            <li>This can be seen in the books of the Kings of Israel and Judah, where the mothers and wives were many times mentioned in relation to a king&rsquo;s success or failure.</li><!--excerpt.end-->
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Kings are not to drink wine [Pro 31:4-7]</li>
    <li>The husband of the proverbs 31 woman is an elder at the gates of the city; i.e., he&rsquo;s a respectable man, yet his wife worked [Pro 31:13-24]. She was no housewife who just sat at home but a businesswoman.
        <ol>
            <li>She wakes up before dawn [Pro 31:15].</li>
            <li>The woman has female servants, not male servants [Pro 31:15].</li>
            <li>It is Biblically okay to borrow for business, but not for consumption [2Kgs 4:3].</li>
            <li>It is okay to have servants [Pro 31:15].
                <ol>
                    <li>Elijah, despite what appears to be his earthly poverty, had servants serve him. Servants are needed, especially in the service of God&rsquo;s servants.</li>
                </ol>
            </li>
            <li>If one wants a harvest, he must be ready to do the work required [Pro 14:4].</li>
            <li>The noble wife has savings, and reinvests them [Pro 31:16]. She bought the field out of her own savings, not from her husbands.</li>
            <li>King Xerxes called for Vashti to display her beauty to his officials, just as God called Job to be displayed before His officials &ndash; the heavenly council.</li>
            <li>The noble woman is nice and generous [Pro 31:20]</li>
            <li><strong>The wife is the one who watches over the affairs of the household, not the husband [Pro 31:27]</strong>.</li>
            <li>A woman is not to be praised for beauty or charm, but for her fear of God, and by implication, the godly attributes that come with it [Pro 31:30].</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Proverbs" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Proverbs" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Proverbs 31 King Lemuel received counsel from his mother, and his mother will share in the glory attributed to him, for she was a part of his upbringing. This can be seen in the books of the Kings of Israel and Judah, where the mothers and wives were many times mentioned in relation to a king&rsquo;s success or failure. Kings are not to drink wine [Pro 31:4-7] The husband of the proverbs 31 woman is an elder at the gates of the city; i.e., he&rsquo;s a respectable man, yet his wife worked [Pro 31:13-24]. She was no housewife who just sat at home but a businesswoman. She wakes up before dawn [Pro 31:15]. The woman has female servants, not male servants [Pro 31:15]. It is Biblically okay to borrow for business, but not for consumption [2Kgs 4:3]. It is okay to have servants [Pro 31:15]. Elijah, despite what appears to be his earthly poverty, had servants serve him. Servants are needed, especially in the service of God&rsquo;s servants. If one wants a harvest, he must be ready to do the work required [Pro 14:4]. The noble wife has savings, and reinvests them [Pro 31:16]. She bought the field out of her own savings, not from her husbands. King Xerxes called for Vashti to display her beauty to his officials, just as God called Job to be displayed before His officials &ndash; the heavenly council. The noble woman is nice and generous [Pro 31:20] The wife is the one who watches over the affairs of the household, not the husband [Pro 31:27]. A woman is not to be praised for beauty or charm, but for her fear of God, and by implication, the godly attributes that come with it [Pro 31:30].]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebrews Overview (03)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(03)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebrews Overview (03)" /><published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hebrews-Overview-(03)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(03)/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Hebrews Overview (03)</h1></header>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>Jesus will render unemployed/idle/useless, the one who holds the power of death [Heb 2:14].
        <ol>
            <li>This is contrary to the belief that Jesus will annihilate/destroy/kill Satan.</li>
            <li>The word translated &lsquo;destroy&rsquo; in the verse is &lsquo;<strong><em>katarg&eacute;ō</em></strong>&rsquo;, means to render something inactive or ineffective<!--excerpt.end-->
                <ol>
                    <li>In Luke 13:7, <strong><em>katarg&eacute;ō </em></strong>means to be useless</li>
                </ol>
            </li>
            <li>Jesus helps Abraham&rsquo;s sons (human beings), not angels [Heb 2:16].
                <ol>
                    <li>This helps guard against those who believe in eternal reconciliation (i.e., the doctrine that God is reconciling Satan and other devils to Himself, along with humans).</li>
                    <li>The doctrine of eternal reconciliation is derived from a misinterpretation of [Colossians 1:20]</li>
                </ol>
            </li>
            <li>Jesus&rsquo; is a compassionate High Priest, as He deals compassionately with the Ignorant and the wayward [Heb 5:1-2].
                <ol>
                    <li>These are the same reasons why God rejected Israel in the wilderness; ignorance and waywardness (<strong><em>plan&aacute;ō</em></strong>) [Heb 3:10]</li>
                    <li>It&rsquo;s not for those who miss the way continually
                        <ol>
                            <li>God says they &lsquo;<strong>always</strong>&rsquo; go astray. This means that our High Priest deals compassionately with those who don&rsquo;t continually go astray [Heb 3:10]</li>
                            <li>The same Hebrews say those who persist in sin will not have cover for their sins [Heb 6:4-8]</li>
                        </ol>
                    </li>
                    <li>He deals with the ignorant by teaching them. He doesn&rsquo;t leave them in ignorance
                        <ol>
                            <li>The Messenger who finds atonement for a man, does so - not only by pleading on his behalf - but also by teaching him what is right for him [Job 33:31-28].</li>
                            <li>Jesus&rsquo; atonement and intercession cannot be different.</li>
                        </ol>
                    </li>
                </ol>
            </li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Angels still intercede for us as Christians under the New Covenant.
        <ol>
            <li>Angels behold the Father&rsquo;s face [Mat18:10] not to exchange pleasantries, but obviously to intercede on our behalf</li>
            <li>Angels who minister to those who will inherit salvation [Heb 1:14].</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Over the centuries (since His ascension), Jesus has not just been interceding for the church, but teaching the Church.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hebrews Overview (03) Jesus will render unemployed/idle/useless, the one who holds the power of death [Heb 2:14]. This is contrary to the belief that Jesus will annihilate/destroy/kill Satan. The word translated &lsquo;destroy&rsquo; in the verse is &lsquo;katarg&eacute;ō&rsquo;, means to render something inactive or ineffective In Luke 13:7, katarg&eacute;ō means to be useless Jesus helps Abraham&rsquo;s sons (human beings), not angels [Heb 2:16]. This helps guard against those who believe in eternal reconciliation (i.e., the doctrine that God is reconciling Satan and other devils to Himself, along with humans). The doctrine of eternal reconciliation is derived from a misinterpretation of [Colossians 1:20] Jesus&rsquo; is a compassionate High Priest, as He deals compassionately with the Ignorant and the wayward [Heb 5:1-2]. These are the same reasons why God rejected Israel in the wilderness; ignorance and waywardness (plan&aacute;ō) [Heb 3:10] It&rsquo;s not for those who miss the way continually God says they &lsquo;always&rsquo; go astray. This means that our High Priest deals compassionately with those who don&rsquo;t continually go astray [Heb 3:10] The same Hebrews say those who persist in sin will not have cover for their sins [Heb 6:4-8] He deals with the ignorant by teaching them. He doesn&rsquo;t leave them in ignorance The Messenger who finds atonement for a man, does so - not only by pleading on his behalf - but also by teaching him what is right for him [Job 33:31-28]. Jesus&rsquo; atonement and intercession cannot be different. Angels still intercede for us as Christians under the New Covenant. Angels behold the Father&rsquo;s face [Mat18:10] not to exchange pleasantries, but obviously to intercede on our behalf Angels who minister to those who will inherit salvation [Heb 1:14]. Over the centuries (since His ascension), Jesus has not just been interceding for the church, but teaching the Church.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1 Cor 11 - Man Head of Woman</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/1%20Cor%2011%20-%20Man%20Head%20of%20Woman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1 Cor 11 - Man Head of Woman" /><published>2023-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/1cor-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/1%20Cor%2011%20-%20Man%20Head%20of%20Woman/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>1<sup>st</sup> Cor 11 - Man Head of Woman</h1></header>
<ul>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>The doctrine Paul taught that women should cover their heads while praying and prophesying is a doctrine of Christ. We know this because, before Paul taught it, he said we should imitate him as he imitates Christ [1Cor 11:1]. Paul was imitating
        Christ, when he taught the doctrine of head covering.</li>
    <li>Paul said he taught only milk to the Corinthians. Therefore, this message of head covering is milk [1Cor 3:1-3].</li><!--excerpt.end-->
    <li>The gospel is not only to believe in Jesus, but the ordinances/traditions that Paul handed down to the Church [1Cor 11:2].</li>
    <li>Paul delivering traditions to the Corinthians (<em>and other Churches</em>) is him imitating Christ [1Cor 11:2,1].</li>
    <li>Man (<em>as a whole</em>) is the head of woman (<em>as a whole</em>), not just husbands being over their wives, just as every general is superior to every sergeant, even though sergeants may be under specific generals and not under every single general
        directly.</li>
</ul>
<h1>Because of the Angels [1Cor 11:10]</h1>
<p>Paul says women are to have a sign of authority over their heads because of the angels [1Cor 11:10]. The gathering of the Church is not simply about Christ, but about God, therefore, the administration of God/the Heaven must be considered.</p>
<ul>
    <li>We are still under the administration of angels [Heb 2:5; Acts 7:53; Gal 3:19; Luk 12:8; 1Tim 5:21; Matt 16:27; Mar 8:38; Luk 9:26].
        <ul>
            <li>Angels make decrees for this age. Heaven as a whole rules over this age [Dan 4:13,17,23-26].</li>
            <li>Nebuchadnezzer and Daniel use the words &lsquo;Most High&rsquo; (God) and &lsquo;Heavens&rsquo; interchangeably. They understand that heaven&rsquo;s decree is God&rsquo;s decree [Dan 4:13,17,23-26]. This is the same reason why the
                New Testament writers use the phrases &lsquo;Kingdom of Heaven&rsquo; and &lsquo;Kingdom of God&rsquo; interchangeably.</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>The Church is God&rsquo;s Church in Christ [1Cor 11:16].</li>
    <li>In the order established by heaven, man is above woman [Gen 2:18 (see LXX translation)]. Even though we are in Christ where man and woman are somewhat equal, we are still under the administration of heaven, and that arrangement must be observed.
        To disrespect it is to disrespect God and the angels (i<em>.e., the heavenly council</em>).</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="1-Corinthians" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="1-Corinthians" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1st Cor 11 - Man Head of Woman The doctrine Paul taught that women should cover their heads while praying and prophesying is a doctrine of Christ. We know this because, before Paul taught it, he said we should imitate him as he imitates Christ [1Cor 11:1]. Paul was imitating Christ, when he taught the doctrine of head covering. Paul said he taught only milk to the Corinthians. Therefore, this message of head covering is milk [1Cor 3:1-3]. The gospel is not only to believe in Jesus, but the ordinances/traditions that Paul handed down to the Church [1Cor 11:2]. Paul delivering traditions to the Corinthians (and other Churches) is him imitating Christ [1Cor 11:2,1]. Man (as a whole) is the head of woman (as a whole), not just husbands being over their wives, just as every general is superior to every sergeant, even though sergeants may be under specific generals and not under every single general directly. Because of the Angels [1Cor 11:10] Paul says women are to have a sign of authority over their heads because of the angels [1Cor 11:10]. The gathering of the Church is not simply about Christ, but about God, therefore, the administration of God/the Heaven must be considered. We are still under the administration of angels [Heb 2:5; Acts 7:53; Gal 3:19; Luk 12:8; 1Tim 5:21; Matt 16:27; Mar 8:38; Luk 9:26]. Angels make decrees for this age. Heaven as a whole rules over this age [Dan 4:13,17,23-26]. Nebuchadnezzer and Daniel use the words &lsquo;Most High&rsquo; (God) and &lsquo;Heavens&rsquo; interchangeably. They understand that heaven&rsquo;s decree is God&rsquo;s decree [Dan 4:13,17,23-26]. This is the same reason why the New Testament writers use the phrases &lsquo;Kingdom of Heaven&rsquo; and &lsquo;Kingdom of God&rsquo; interchangeably. The Church is God&rsquo;s Church in Christ [1Cor 11:16]. In the order established by heaven, man is above woman [Gen 2:18 (see LXX translation)]. Even though we are in Christ where man and woman are somewhat equal, we are still under the administration of heaven, and that arrangement must be observed. To disrespect it is to disrespect God and the angels (i.e., the heavenly council).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebrews Overview (02)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(02)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebrews Overview (02)" /><published>2023-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hebrews-Overview-(02)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(02)/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Hebrews Overview (02)</h1></header>
<h1>Sin</h1>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>Sin can be an action</li>
    <li>Sins can be an object (I.e., the object used in committing a sin like an idol)</li>
    <li>Sin can be a person [<em>Gen 4:7</em>]</li><!--excerpt.end-->
</ol>
<h1>Life</h1>
<ol>
    <li>Life is access to blessings</li>
    <li>Life is access to God&rsquo;s presence</li>
    <li>To enjoy life in this world, one needs a body</li>
</ol>
<h1>Death</h1>
<ol>
    <li>Death is banishment [<em>2Sam 14:14</em>]</li>
    <li>Life isn&rsquo;t simply the existence of a soul, but access to God&rsquo;s presence and to blessings.</li>
    <li>When God drives a person away from His presence, it is called death.</li>
</ol>
<h1>Proximity to God Issues</h1>
<ol>
    <li>Proximity to God is a delicate matter, as He can kill those close to Him who sin against Him [<em>Exo 33:1-3, 5</em>].</li>
    <li>Being far from God comes with its drawbacks, as being far from Him cuts us off from blessings (<em>and also exposes one to evil powers</em>)</li>
</ol>
<h1>The Day of Atonement [<em>Lev 16</em>]</h1>
<ol>
    <li>One goat was to be offered to Yahweh and another to Azazel</li>
    <li>The sacrifices would cleanse the tabernacle</li>
    <li>This means that the sins of the people defiled the tabernacle</li>
</ol>
<h1>Why Do We Need Jesus&rsquo; Intercession?</h1>
<ol>
    <li>Two things take care of sins in Hebrews; the atonement of Jesus and His intercession.</li>
    <li>We need Jesus&rsquo; intercession because the devil still has access to God&rsquo;s presence</li>
    <li>Job was not a Jew, yet he was accused by Satan</li>
    <li>Which means Satan does not need the Law to accuse.</li>
    <li>The Law makes it easy for Satan to accuse, but he still can</li>
    <li>This means that Satan does not need the Law to accuse Christians</li>
</ol>
<h1>Why One Sacrifice is Sufficient</h1>
<ol>
    <li>It is appointed for men to die <strong>ONCE </strong>[<em>Heb 9:28</em>]</li>
    <li>The sacrifice represents us (sinners)</li>
    <li>Since Jesus died for us, then we are dead</li>
    <li>As far as the Law is concerned, we are dead, and it cannot judge us</li>
    <li>The dead cannot sin, and we are dead in Christ and so, the requirement of the Law against those who sin is gone, as the Law calls for death, and we are already dead</li>
</ol>
<h1>The Problem of the Law</h1>
<ol>
    <li>The Law is a shadow. It cannot produce the result that the true would produce [<em>Heb 10:1</em>].
        <ol>
            <li>The Law could accomplish some things, but could not do the main job.</li>
            <li>The external rituals of the Law such as the anointing oil had effects</li>
            <li>The Lord Supper, the Baptism, Nazirite vows, laying on of hands, anointing people with oil, etc are all rituals in the New Covenant.</li>
            <li>The anointing with oil came from under the Law. This shows that those rituals, still have effect in the New Covenant.</li>
            <li>We must not disregard those rituals, but must understand them to know which can apply to us as New Covenant believers.</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>Not every part of the Law was a shadow. There were real aspects to the Law
        <ol>
            <li>God was real</li>
            <li>The holy Spirit was real</li>
            <li>The Glory of God was real</li>
            <li>Sin was real.</li>
            <li>The Tabernacle was a shadow</li>
            <li>The feast days were shadows</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>The priesthood of the Law was ineffective because the accuser didn&rsquo;t accuse from the tabernacle, where the high priest was, but accuses in God&rsquo;s very presence</li>
    <li>The mortality of the priests of the Law also limited their priesthood</li>
</ol>
<h1>The Problem with the Sacrifices of the Law</h1>
<ol>
    <li>The Purpose of the sacrifices of the Law was to ratify the covenant
        <ol>
            <li>There were various sacrifices under the Law, but they represented the One real sacrifice of the New Covenant</li>
        </ol>
    </li>
    <li>The blood is meant to bind the people and the tabernacle, under the terms of the covenant. The most appropriate blood would be that of the high priest [<em>Heb 9:25</em>], and the blood of bulls and goats is insufficient to do this.</li>
    <li>Jesus&rsquo; sacrifice used His own blood.</li>
    <li>The sacrifice is meant to make holy [<em>Heb 2:11; 10:10; 13:12</em>]</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hebrews Overview (02) Sin Sin can be an action Sins can be an object (I.e., the object used in committing a sin like an idol) Sin can be a person [Gen 4:7] Life Life is access to blessings Life is access to God&rsquo;s presence To enjoy life in this world, one needs a body Death Death is banishment [2Sam 14:14] Life isn&rsquo;t simply the existence of a soul, but access to God&rsquo;s presence and to blessings. When God drives a person away from His presence, it is called death. Proximity to God Issues Proximity to God is a delicate matter, as He can kill those close to Him who sin against Him [Exo 33:1-3, 5]. Being far from God comes with its drawbacks, as being far from Him cuts us off from blessings (and also exposes one to evil powers) The Day of Atonement [Lev 16] One goat was to be offered to Yahweh and another to Azazel The sacrifices would cleanse the tabernacle This means that the sins of the people defiled the tabernacle Why Do We Need Jesus&rsquo; Intercession? Two things take care of sins in Hebrews; the atonement of Jesus and His intercession. We need Jesus&rsquo; intercession because the devil still has access to God&rsquo;s presence Job was not a Jew, yet he was accused by Satan Which means Satan does not need the Law to accuse. The Law makes it easy for Satan to accuse, but he still can This means that Satan does not need the Law to accuse Christians Why One Sacrifice is Sufficient It is appointed for men to die ONCE [Heb 9:28] The sacrifice represents us (sinners) Since Jesus died for us, then we are dead As far as the Law is concerned, we are dead, and it cannot judge us The dead cannot sin, and we are dead in Christ and so, the requirement of the Law against those who sin is gone, as the Law calls for death, and we are already dead The Problem of the Law The Law is a shadow. It cannot produce the result that the true would produce [Heb 10:1]. The Law could accomplish some things, but could not do the main job. The external rituals of the Law such as the anointing oil had effects The Lord Supper, the Baptism, Nazirite vows, laying on of hands, anointing people with oil, etc are all rituals in the New Covenant. The anointing with oil came from under the Law. This shows that those rituals, still have effect in the New Covenant. We must not disregard those rituals, but must understand them to know which can apply to us as New Covenant believers. Not every part of the Law was a shadow. There were real aspects to the Law God was real The holy Spirit was real The Glory of God was real Sin was real. The Tabernacle was a shadow The feast days were shadows The priesthood of the Law was ineffective because the accuser didn&rsquo;t accuse from the tabernacle, where the high priest was, but accuses in God&rsquo;s very presence The mortality of the priests of the Law also limited their priesthood The Problem with the Sacrifices of the Law The Purpose of the sacrifices of the Law was to ratify the covenant There were various sacrifices under the Law, but they represented the One real sacrifice of the New Covenant The blood is meant to bind the people and the tabernacle, under the terms of the covenant. The most appropriate blood would be that of the high priest [Heb 9:25], and the blood of bulls and goats is insufficient to do this. Jesus&rsquo; sacrifice used His own blood. The sacrifice is meant to make holy [Heb 2:11; 10:10; 13:12]]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebrews Overview (01)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(01)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebrews Overview (01)" /><published>2023-07-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hebrews-Overview-(01)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hebrews%20Overview%20(01)/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Hebrews Overview (01)</h1></header>
<ol>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>God spoke through prophets and angels in the past [<em>Heb 1:1</em>]</li>
    <li>He spoke through His Son in the latter times [<em>Heb 1:2</em>]</li><!--excerpt.end-->
    <li>The message spoken by prophets, angels and the Son is salvation [<em>Heb 1:1-2; 2:2-3</em>]</li>
    <li>The salvation is through Jesus Himself [<em>Heb 2:10</em>]</li>
    <li>The message carries a heavy warning, because it is from the Son [<em>Heb 2:1-3</em>]</li>
    <li>The message is a command, and not a suggestion [<em>Act 17:30-31</em>]</li>
    <li>This present age is subject to angels [<em>Heb 2:5</em>]</li>
    <li>The age to come is subjected to man (i.e., glorified sons of God) [<em>Heb 2:5</em>].</li>
    <li>Man is not yet mature enough (i.e., not yet glorified) for the earth to be handed over to him [<em>Heb 2:6-8</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus is the head of this new glorified man [<em>Heb 2:9</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus however has been glorified [<em>Heb 2:9</em>].</li>
    <li>God wants to bring many sons to glory, but the author of the epistle takes for granted that his audience might not know what he means. He didn&rsquo;t bother explaining it [<em>Heb 2:10</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus is the author of our salvation [<em>Heb 2:9-10</em>].</li>
    <li>The goal of salvation is perfection [<em>Heb 2:10</em>].</li>
    <li>Perfection is to be complete.</li>
    <li>The message is Jesus bringing many sons to glory [<em>Heb 2:10</em>].</li>
    <li>The author again takes for granted that the devil has the power of death, and that Jesus is to destroy the devil. He doesn&rsquo;t expatiate [<em>Heb 2:14</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus helps Abraham&rsquo;s descendants</li>
    <li>Not just Abraham&rsquo;s descendants, but men since the foundation of the world [<em>Heb 9:25-26</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus appeared at the end of the world [<em>Heb 9:26</em>] (Bonus point).</li>
    <li>The second death is for men and angels [<em>Rev 20:10</em>], but the author says Jesus&rsquo; death is only for flesh and blood; not for angels [<em>Heb 2:14-16</em>].</li>
    <li>Jesus had to become a man, so that he could be a merciful and faithful High Priest. And make atonement for the sins of the people [<em>Heb 2:17</em>]. To make sure Jesus is merciful and faithful, He had to become flesh and blood. This is the message
        of the book of Hebrews.</li>
    <li>In order to partake of the glory that Jesus brings, we have to hold on to Jesus [<em>Heb 3:6</em>].</li>
    <li>The word of God is discerns/judges sins, the word of God is going to expose sin [<em>Heb 4:12-13</em>].</li>
    <li>Chapter 2 presented Jesus&rsquo; high priesthood and atonement, in Chapter 4, the author begins to focus on the high priesthood of Jesus, and will deal with the atonement later</li>
    <li>The mercy of Jesus&rsquo; priesthood has to do with His ability to sympathize with our weakness [<em>Heb 4:15</em>].</li>
    <li>God is the one who said Christ is His Son, and in doing so, makes Him [<em>the High</em>] Priest [<em>Heb 5:1-6</em>].</li>
    <li>Perfection is for those who <strong>OBEY</strong> Jesus [<em>Heb 5:9</em>].</li>
    <li>The summary is that Jesus was appointed by God. He didn&rsquo;t make Himself High Priest.</li>
    <li>The two immutable/unchangeable things of Hebrews 6:18 are the oath to bless Abraham with many descendants, and the oath to Jesus that He would be a priest forever in the order of Melchizedek.</li>
    <li>Drawing near to God is a goal of God for us [<em>Heb 7:19</em>], but again, the author says it in passing; like it&rsquo;s something with which his audience is familiar.</li>
    <li>The main activity of Jesus as our high priest is intercession [<em>Heb 7:25</em>].</li>
    <li>God does not need the Law to condemn sinners (<em>see Job, and other sins before the Law</em>).</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Hebrews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hebrews Overview (01) God spoke through prophets and angels in the past [Heb 1:1] He spoke through His Son in the latter times [Heb 1:2] The message spoken by prophets, angels and the Son is salvation [Heb 1:1-2; 2:2-3] The salvation is through Jesus Himself [Heb 2:10] The message carries a heavy warning, because it is from the Son [Heb 2:1-3] The message is a command, and not a suggestion [Act 17:30-31] This present age is subject to angels [Heb 2:5] The age to come is subjected to man (i.e., glorified sons of God) [Heb 2:5]. Man is not yet mature enough (i.e., not yet glorified) for the earth to be handed over to him [Heb 2:6-8]. Jesus is the head of this new glorified man [Heb 2:9]. Jesus however has been glorified [Heb 2:9]. God wants to bring many sons to glory, but the author of the epistle takes for granted that his audience might not know what he means. He didn&rsquo;t bother explaining it [Heb 2:10]. Jesus is the author of our salvation [Heb 2:9-10]. The goal of salvation is perfection [Heb 2:10]. Perfection is to be complete. The message is Jesus bringing many sons to glory [Heb 2:10]. The author again takes for granted that the devil has the power of death, and that Jesus is to destroy the devil. He doesn&rsquo;t expatiate [Heb 2:14]. Jesus helps Abraham&rsquo;s descendants Not just Abraham&rsquo;s descendants, but men since the foundation of the world [Heb 9:25-26]. Jesus appeared at the end of the world [Heb 9:26] (Bonus point). The second death is for men and angels [Rev 20:10], but the author says Jesus&rsquo; death is only for flesh and blood; not for angels [Heb 2:14-16]. Jesus had to become a man, so that he could be a merciful and faithful High Priest. And make atonement for the sins of the people [Heb 2:17]. To make sure Jesus is merciful and faithful, He had to become flesh and blood. This is the message of the book of Hebrews. In order to partake of the glory that Jesus brings, we have to hold on to Jesus [Heb 3:6]. The word of God is discerns/judges sins, the word of God is going to expose sin [Heb 4:12-13]. Chapter 2 presented Jesus&rsquo; high priesthood and atonement, in Chapter 4, the author begins to focus on the high priesthood of Jesus, and will deal with the atonement later The mercy of Jesus&rsquo; priesthood has to do with His ability to sympathize with our weakness [Heb 4:15]. God is the one who said Christ is His Son, and in doing so, makes Him [the High] Priest [Heb 5:1-6]. Perfection is for those who OBEY Jesus [Heb 5:9]. The summary is that Jesus was appointed by God. He didn&rsquo;t make Himself High Priest. The two immutable/unchangeable things of Hebrews 6:18 are the oath to bless Abraham with many descendants, and the oath to Jesus that He would be a priest forever in the order of Melchizedek. Drawing near to God is a goal of God for us [Heb 7:19], but again, the author says it in passing; like it&rsquo;s something with which his audience is familiar. The main activity of Jesus as our high priest is intercession [Heb 7:25]. God does not need the Law to condemn sinners (see Job, and other sins before the Law).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Psalms 17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Psalms%2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Psalms 17" /><published>2023-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Psalms-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Psalms%2017/"><![CDATA[<header><h1>Psalms 17</h1></header>
<h2>Elencho - to rebuke [<em>Joh 16:8-11</em>]</h2>
<ul>
    <!--excerpt.start--><li>Elencho means to rebuke</li>
    <li>Elencho does not always mean that the one rebuked repents of his sin as was the case with Herod when John the Baptist rebuked (Elencho) him of his sin [<em>Luk 3:19-20</em>]</li><!--excerpt.end-->
    <li>Elencho can be rebuke to make others fear[<em>1Tim 1:4</em>]</li>
    <li>Elencho can mean to rebuke people in the hope of bringing them to faith [<em>Tit 1:12</em>].</li>
    <li>The Sprit of truth will Elencho the world of sin, righteousness and judgment [<em>Joh 16:8-11</em>]</li>
    <li>The Spirit of truth does His work by the testimony of Jesus, and by the working of miracles.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Posts-Summaries" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Psalms" /><category term="Year-2023" /><category term="Psalms" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Psalms 17 Elencho - to rebuke [Joh 16:8-11] Elencho means to rebuke Elencho does not always mean that the one rebuked repents of his sin as was the case with Herod when John the Baptist rebuked (Elencho) him of his sin [Luk 3:19-20] Elencho can be rebuke to make others fear[1Tim 1:4] Elencho can mean to rebuke people in the hope of bringing them to faith [Tit 1:12]. The Sprit of truth will Elencho the world of sin, righteousness and judgment [Joh 16:8-11] The Spirit of truth does His work by the testimony of Jesus, and by the working of miracles.]]></summary></entry></feed>